swissotel.com 2019-11-20

# Accor Hotels : GLOBAL HOTEL GUEST PRIVACY POLICY

## 1\. THE ACCORHOTELS GROUP'S COMMITMENT TO PROTECTING PRIVACY

We consider you an important customer. Our first priority is to offer you exceptional stays and experiences throughout the world.

**Your complete satisfaction and confidence in AccorHotels is absolutely essential to us.**

That's why, as part of our commitment to meeting your expectations, we have set up (and we had a privacy policy before the much anticipated GDPR - General Data Protection Regulation ;-)) a **customer personal data protection charter**. This charter formalizes our commitments to you and describes how the AccorHotels Group uses your personal data.

Top of page

## 2\. SCOPE OF APPLICATION

In this charter, “AccorHotels Group” means:

  * Accor SA, the AccorHotels Group parent company, with registered offices at 82 rue Henri Farman, 92130 Issy-les-Moulineaux, France;
  * Subsidiary or “family” companies of Accor SA involved in the hotel businesses of the AccorHotels Group; and
  * hotels operated under one of the AccorHotels Group brands throughout the world (Raffles, Sofitel Legend, Fairmont, SO/, Sofitel, onefinestay, Rixos, MGallery, Pullman, Swissôtel, 25hours Hotels, Novotel, Mercure, Mama Shelter, Adagio, JO&JOE, ibis, ibis Styles, ibis budget, Grand Mercure, The Sebel and hotelF1). This list of brands is regularly updated and can be viewed on [accorhotels.com](https://www.accorhotels.com/).

**Good to know!**

You probably don't know this, but the hotel you are booked to stay in is probably not owned by Accor SA or one of its family of companies. Most AccorHotels branded hotels are operated under a franchise or management agreement between the hotel’s owner and Accor SA (or one of its subsidiaries across the world).

This is why, when staying in one of these hotels, your personal data will be dealt with by Accor SA and the hotel, both acting as Data Controllers for their own, separate, purposes. In summary:

  * Accor SA will process your data because it manages a central booking engine, which allows Accor SA to collect the data necessary to organise your stay in hotels under an AccorHotels brand and to communicate this data to the concerned hotels. Accor SA also manages a global database of clients who stay in hotels under an AccorHotels brand. With the help of its subsidiary PRO-FID SAS, Accor SA also manages the Le Club AccorHotels loyalty programme;

  * Each hotel will process your data to manage its contractual relationship with you (invoicing, payment, booking management etc.), to perform marketing activities and to comply with its legal obligations.

Accor SA has communicated the principles set out in this charter to all of the AccorHotels branded hotels and their respective owners. We will do our upmost to ensure that all hotels comply with the applicable data protection laws and this charter in relation to the processing of your personal data.

Top of page

## 3\. AccorHotels' TEN PRINCIPLES FOR PROTECTING YOUR PERSONAL DATA

In accordance with applicable regulations, in particular the European General Data Protection Regulation, we have instituted the following ten principles throughout the AccorHotels Group:

  1. **Lawfulness:** We use personal data only if: 
    * we obtain the **consent** of the person, OR
    * it is necessary to do so for the **performance** of a contract to which the person is a party, OR
    * it is necessary for **compliance** with a legal obligation, OR
    * it is necessary in order to protect the **vital interests** of the person, OR
    * we have a **legitimate interest** in using personal data and our usage does not adversely affect the persons’ rights
  2. **Fairness:** We can explain why we need the personal data we collect.
    * **Purpose limitation and data minimisation:** We only use personal data that we really need. If the result can be achieved with less personal data, then we make sure we use the minimum data required.
  3. **Transparency:** We inform people about the way we use their personal data
  4. We facilitate the exercise of the people’s **rights** : access to their personal data, rectification and erasure of their personal data and the right to object to the use of their personal data
  5. **Storage limitation:** We retain personal data for a limited period
    * We ensure the security of personal data, i.e. its **integrity and confidentiality**.
    * If a **third party** uses personal data, we make sure it has the capacity to protect that personal data.
  6. If personal data is transferred outside Europe, we ensure this **transfer** is covered by specific legal tools.
  7. If personal data is compromised (lost, stolen, damaged, unavailable…), we notify such breaches to the respective country’s responsible authority and to the person concerned, if the **breach** is likely to cause a high-risk in respect of the rights and freedoms of this person.

For any questions concerning the ten principles of AccorHotels data protection policies, please contact the Data Privacy department whose details appear in the clause **"Your rights"**.

Top of page

## 4\. WHAT PERSONAL DATA IS COLLECTED?

At various times, we may collect information about you and/or the persons accompanying you, including the following:

  * Contact details (for example, last name, first name, telephone number, email)
  * Personal information (for example, date of birth, nationality)
  * Information relating to your children (for example, first name, date of birth, age)
  * Your credit card number (for transaction and reservation purposes)
  * Information contained on a form of identification (such as ID card, passport or driver licence)
  * Your membership number for the AccorHotels loyalty program or another partner program (for example, an airline loyalty programme) and information related to your activities within the context of the loyalty program
  * Your arrival and departure dates
  * Your preferences and interests (for example, smoking or non-smoking room, preferred floor, type of bedding, type of newspapers/magazines, sports, cultural interests, food and beverages preferences, etc.)
  * Your questions/comments, during or following a stay in one of our AccorHotels branded establishments
  * Technical and location data you generate as a result of using our websites and applications.

The information collected in relation to persons under 16 years of age is limited to their name, nationality and date of birth, which can only be supplied to us by an adult. We would be grateful if you could ensure that your children do not send us any personal data without your consent (particularly via the Internet). If such data is sent, you can contact the Data Privacy department (see clause **"Your rights"** below) to arrange for this information to be deleted.

In order to meet your requirements or provide you with a specific service (such as dietary requirements), we may have to collect sensitive information, such as information concerning race, ethnicity, political opinions, religious and philosophical beliefs, union membership, or details of health or sexual orientation. In this case, we will only process this data if you provide your express prior consent.

Top of page

## 5.WHEN IS YOUR PERSONAL DATA COLLECTED?

Personal data may be collected on a variety of occasions, including:

  1. Hotel activities: 
    * Booking a room
    * Checking-in and paying
    * Hotel stays and services provided during a stay
    * Eating/drinking at the hotel bar or restaurant during a stay
    * Requests, complaints and/or disputes.
  2. Participation in marketing programs or events: 
    * Signing up for loyalty programs
    * Participation in customer surveys (for example, the Guest Satisfaction Survey)
    * Online games or competitions
    * Subscription to newsletters, in order to receive offers and promotions via email.
  3. Transmission of information from third parties: 
    * Tour operators, travel agencies (online or not), GDS reservation systems and others
  4. Internet activities: 
    * Connection to AccorHotels websites (IP address, cookies in accordance with our [Policy about the use of tracers](https://www.accorhotels.com/security-certificate/cookies-policy.en.shtml))
    * Online forms (online reservation, questionnaires, AccorHotels pages on social networks, social networks login devices such as Facebook login, conversations with chatbot, etc.).

Top of page

## 6\. WHAT PURPOSES IS YOUR DATA COLLECTED FOR AND HOW LONG DO WE RETAIN IT?

The table below sets out why we process your data, the lawful basis for the processing and the associated retention period:

**Purpose/Activity**

| 

**Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest**

| 

**Retention period**  
  
---|---|---  
  
Meeting our obligations to our customers.

| 

Performance of a contract with you.

Necessary to comply with a legal obligation.

Necessary for our legitimate interest in running our business and providing you with requested products and services.

| 

10 years from the booking in accordance with legal obligations.  
  
Managing the reservation of rooms and accommodation requests, in particular the creation and storage of legal documents in compliance with accounting standards.  
  
Managing your stay at the hotel:

  * Managing access to rooms
  * Monitoring your use of services (telephone, bar, pay TV etc.)

| 

Performance of a contract with you.

Necessary for our legitimate interest in running our business and providing you with requested products and services.

| 

For the duration of your stay.  
  
Managing our relationship with customers before, during and after your stay:

  * Managing the loyalty program
  * Inputting details into the customer database
  * Segmentation analysis based on reservation history and customer travel preferences with a view to sending targeted communications, subject to the requirements of the EU ePrivacy directive (2002/58/EC as amended in 2009)
  * Predicting and anticipating future customer behaviors
  * Developing statistics, commercial scores and carrying out reporting of the same
  * Providing context data for our marketing tools. This happens when a customer visits a Group website or makes a reservation
  * Understanding and managing the preferences of new or repeat customers
  * Sending customers newsletters, promotions, tourist, hotel or service offers, offers from Accor SA or its commercial partners, or contacting you by telephone subject to the requirements of the EU ePrivacy directive (2002/58/EG as amended in 2009)

| 

Performance of our contract with you and for the management of your membership in the loyalty program.

Necessary for our legitimate interests in promoting our services, performing direct marketing activities (taking into account your commercial relationship with one of the AccorHotels Group’s entities) and improving our services.

| 

3 years from the last date on which you have interacted with us in any way, if you are not a member of the loyalty programme.

6 years from the last date on which you have interacted with us in any way, if you are a member of the loyalty programme.  
  
Improving our hotel service by:

  * Personalising your check-in, improving the quality of service and customer experience
  * Processing your personal data through our customer marketing program in order to carry out marketing operations, promote brands and gain a better understanding of your requirements and wishes
  * Adapting our products and services to better meet your requirements
  * Customising the commercial offers and promotional messages we send you
  * Informing you of special offers and any new services created by Accor SA or one of its subsidiaries or commercial partners.

| 

Performance of contract with you in relation to the management of your membership in the loyalty program.

Necessary for our legitimate interests in promoting our services, performing direct marketing activities (taking into account your commercial relationship with AccorHotels Group) and improving our services.

| 

3 years from the last date on which you have interacted with us in any way, if you are not a member of the loyalty program.

6 years from the last date on which you have interacted with us in any way, if you are a member of the loyalty program.  
  
Use a trusted third party to cross-check, analyse and combine your collected data at the time of booking or at the time of your stay, in order to determine your interests and develop your customer profile and to allow us to send you personalized offers.

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests in promoting our services, performing direct marketing activities (taking into account your commercial relationship with one of the AccorHotels Group’s entities)) and improving our services.

| 

3 years from the last date on which you have interacted with us in any way, if you are not a member of the loyalty program.

6 years from the last date on which you have interacted with us in any way, if you are a member of the loyalty program.  
  
Improving Accor SA services, in particular:

  * Carrying out surveys and analyses of questionnaires and customer comments
  * Managing claims/complaints
  * Offering you the benefits of our loyalty program.

| 

Performance of contract with you (for the management of your membership in the loyalty program)

Necessary for our legitimate interests in promoting our services, performing direct marketing activities (taking into account your commercial relationship with one of the AccorHotels Group’s entities)) and improving our services.

| 

3 years from the last date on which you have interacted with us in any way, if you are not a member of the loyalty program.

6 years from the last date on which you have interacted with us in any way, if you are a member of the loyalty program.

6 years from the date of closure of your file in case of a claim or a complaint.  
  
Securing and enhancing your use of Accor SA websites, applications and services by:

  * Improving navigation;
  * Maintenance and support; and
  * Implementing security and fraud prevention.

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests in running our business, provision of administration and IT services and network security to prevent fraud

| 

13 months from the collection of the information.  
  
Internal management of lists of customers having behaved inappropriately during their stay at the hotel (aggressive and anti-social behaviour, non-compliance with safety regulations, theft, damage and vandalism or payment incidents).

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests in running our business and to prevent fraud and the abuse of our property and staff.

| 

Up to 122 days from the recording of an event.  
  
Securing payments by determining the associated level of fraud risk. As part of this analysis, Accor SA and hotels may use the AccorHotels Group risk prevention service provider to refine their analysis.

Depending on the results of the investigations carried out, AccorHotels Group may take security measures, in particular AccorHotels Group may request the use of a different booking channel or for the use of an alternative payment method. These measures will have the effect of suspending the execution of the booking or, if the result of the analysis does not guarantee the safety of the order, of cancelling it. Fraudulent use of a means of payment leading to payment default may result in the entry of data in the AccorHotels Group incident file, which may lead AccorHotels Group to block future payments or carry out additional checks.

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests in running our business and to prevent fraud.

| 

90 days to our database to allow for analysis and controls and then 2 years in a separated database used for improving the system.

In case of recording in the incident file, 2 years from recording or until regularization of the situation if earlier.  
  
Securing properties and persons and preventing non-payments.

For these reasons, some hotels have a feature that allow them to include in the category of "ineffective" customers, any customer whose behaviour has been inappropriate in the following ways: aggression and rudeness, non-compliance with the hotel contract, failure to observe safety rules, theft, damage and vandalism, or payment issues. The status of “ineffective” may cause the hotel where this listing originated to refuse a customer's reservation when he/she returns to the same hotel.

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests in running our business, securing properties and persons and preventing non-payments.

| 

122 days from registration.  
  
Using services to search for persons staying in AccorHotels Group hotels in the event of serious events affecting the hotel in question (natural disasters, terrorist attacks, etc.).

| 

Protection of the vital interests of the guests.

| 

For the duration of the event.  
  
Conforming to any applicable legislation (for example, storing of accounting documents), including:

  * Managing requests to unsubscribe from newsletters, promotions, tourist offers and satisfaction surveys
  * Managing data subject’s requests regarding their personal data.

| 

Necessary to comply with a legal obligation.

| 

As stipulated in the respective country’s legislation.  
  
Top of page

## 7\. CONDITIONS OF THIRD-PARTY ACCESS TO YOUR PERSONAL DATA

The AccorHotels Group operates in many countries and we endeavour to provide you with the same services throughout the world. Thus, we have to share your personal data with internal and external recipients subject to the following conditions:

  1. **We share your data with a number of authorised people and departments in the AccorHotels Group in order to offer you the best experience in our hotels. The following teams may have access to your data:**
    * Hotel staff
    * Reservation staff using AccorHotels reservation tools
    * IT departments
    * Commercial partners and marketing services
    * Medical services if applicable
    * Legal services if applicable
    * Generally, any appropriate person within AccorHotels Group entities for certain specific categories of personal data.

**In particular, the data related to your stays, preferences, satisfaction and, if the case may be, your loyalty program membership are shared between the hotels operating under the AccorHotels Group brands. This data is used to improve the quality of service and your experience in each of these hotels. In this context, your data is processed jointly by Accor SA and these hotels. In order to pursue this legitimate interest, whilst safeguarding your rights and liberties, a specific joint controllership agreement describes the obligations and responsibilities of Accor SA and these hotels. You may, at any time, object to the sharing of this data between the hotels and Accor SA by contacting the Data Privacy department whose details appear in the clause"Your rights". You can also request a summary of the key points of the joint controllership agreement.**

  2. **With service providers and partners:** your personal data may be sent to a third party for the purposes of supplying you with services and improving your stay, for example:
    * External service providers: IT sub-contractors, international call centres, banks, credit card issuers, external lawyers, dispatchers, printers.
    * Commercial partners: Accor SA may, unless you specify otherwise to the Data Privacy department, enhance your profile by sharing certain personal information with its preferred commercial partners. In this case, a trusted third party may cross-check, analyse and combine your data. This data processing will allow Accor SA and its privileged contractual partners to determine your interests and customer profile to allow us to send you personalized offers.
    * Social networking sites: In order to allow you to be identified on the AccorHotels website without the need to fill out a registration form, Accor SA has put in place a social network login system. If you log in using the social network login system, you explicitly authorize Accor SA to access and store the public data on your social network account (e.g. Facebook, LinkedIn, Google, Instagram…), as well as other data stated during use of such social network login system. Accor SA may also communicate your email address to social networks in order to identify whether you are already a user of the concerned social network and in order to post personalized, relevant adverts on your social network account if appropriate.
  3. **With local authorities:** We may be obliged to send your information to local authorities if this is required by law or as part of an inquiry. We will ensure that any such transfer is carried out in accordance with local regulations.

Top of page

## 8\. PROTECTION OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA DURING INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS

For the purposes set out in clause 6 of this charter, we may transfer your personal data to internal or external recipients who may be in countries offering different levels of personal data protection.

Consequently, in addition to implementation of this charter, AccorHotels employs appropriate measures to ensure secure transfer of your personal data to an AccorHotels entity or to an external recipient located in a country offering a different level of privacy from that in the country where the personal data was collected.

Your data may be sent, in particular as part of the reservation process, to AccorHotels hotels located outside of the European Union, in particular in the following countries: South Africa, Algeria, Andorra, Angola, Saudi Arabia, Argentina, Australia, Bahrain, Benin, Brazil, Cambodia, Cameroon, Canada, Chile, China, Colombia, South Korea, Ivory Coast, Cuba, Egypt, United Arab Emirates, Ecuador, United States of America, Fiji, Ghana, Guatemala, Equatorial Guinea, India, Indonesia, Israel, Japan, Jordan, Kuwait, Laos, Lebanon, Madagascar, Malaysia, Morocco, Mauritius, Mexico, Monaco, Myanmar, Nigeria, New Zealand, Oman, Uzbekistan, Panama, Paraguay, Peru, Philippines, Qatar, Democratic Republic of Congo, Dominican Republic, Russia, Senegal, Singapore, Switzerland, Chad, Thailand, Togo, Tunisia, Turkmenistan, Turkey, Ukraine, Uruguay, Vietnam, Yemen, Taiwan, Hong Kong, Macao, Dubai.

Other than those that are required to carry out your reservation, data transfers to countries having different levels of personal data protection, are regulated by standard contractual clauses defined by the European Commission. Data transfers to the United States may also be made to entities that belong to the US-Privacy Shield.

Top of page

## 9\. DATA SECURITY

Accor SA takes appropriate technical and organizational measures, in accordance with applicable legal provisions (in particular: Art. 32 GDPR), to protect your personal data against illicit or accidental destruction, alteration or loss misuse and unauthorized access, modification or disclosure. To this end, we have taken technical measures (such as firewalls) and organizational measures (such as a user ID/password system, means of physical protection etc.) to ensure the ongoing confidentiality, integrity, availability and resilience of processing systems and services. In relation to the submission of credit card data when making a reservation, SSL (Secure Socket Layer) encryption technology is used to guarantee a secure transaction. Organizational measures ensure the security of the processing.

Top of page

## 10\. COOKIES

Accor SA uses cookies or other tracers on its websites. To learn more about the way AccorHotels uses tracers and to configure them, please consult our [Policy about the use of tracers](https://www.accorhotels.com/security-certificate/cookies-policy.en.shtml).

Top of page

## 11\. YOUR RIGHTS

You have the right to obtain information about and access your personal data collected by Accor SA, subject to applicable legal provisions. Also you have the right to have your personal data rectified, erased or have the processing of it restricted. Furthermore you have the right to data portability and to issue instructions on how your data is to be treated after your death (hopefully as late as possible!). You can also object to the processing of your personal data, in particular to the sharing of the data related to your stays, preferences and satisfaction between the hotels operating under the AccorHotels Group brands.

In the event that you wish to exercise any of your above rights, please contact the Data Privacy department for the AccorHotels Group directly by sending an email to [data.privacy@accor.com](mailto:data.privacy@Accor.com) or by writing to the address below:

**_Accor  _**

**_Département Protection des Données Personnelles  (Data Privacy Department)_**

_82, rue Henri Farman -_ _ACC 1208_

_CS 20077_

_92445 Issy-les-Moulineaux - FRANCE_

For the purposes of confidentiality and personal data protection, we will need to check your identity in order to respond to your request. In case of reasonable doubts concerning your identity you may be asked to include a copy of an official piece of identification, such as an ID card or passport, along with your request. A black and white copy of the relevant page of your identity document is sufficient.

All requests will receive a response as swiftly as possible.

You may also exercise your rights in respect of your personal data that is stored and processed by a hotel as a data controller. To do this, you must contact the hotel directly. You will find all necessary information to contact a hotel on [www.accorhotels.com](https://www.accorhotels.com/). If you need any assistance, please contact AccorHotels Data Privacy Department by writing to [data.privacy@accor.com](mailto:data.privacy@Accor.com) or to the above postal address.

You also have the right to lodge a complaint with a [data protection authority](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm). For your information,

You can contact AccorHotels data protection officer by writing to accorhotels.dpo(at)accor.com or to the above postal address.

If you are in Australia or New Zealand and have a complaint about how we collect, hold, use or disclose your personal data, you can also contact [privacy.au@accor.com](mailto:privacy.au@accor.com).

Top of page

## 12\. UPDATES

We may modify this charter from time to time. Consequently, we recommend that you consult it regularly, particularly when making a reservation at one of our hotels.

Top of page

## 13\. QUESTIONS AND CONTACTS

For any questions concerning the AccorHotels Group's personal data protection policy, please contact the Data Privacy department (See clause **"Your rights"** ).

Top of page
